blastingpop.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy - Blasting News

**Consent to the Collection and Processing of your Personal Data**

We hereby inform you that the company Blasting Sagl (“Blasting”) collects and processes your Personal Data (as defined below), as a result of your being a user of its internet portal www.blastingnews.com in accordance with the privacy requirements established by (a) the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection of June 19, 1992 (as further amended from time to time, the “ _FADP_ ”) and related legislation, (b) the Italian Legislative Decree of June 30, 2003, no. 196 (the “ _Privacy Code_ ”), and (c) the Italian regulation “ _Simplified Arrangements to Provide Information and Obtain Consent Regarding Cookies_ ”, issued by the Italian Data Protection Authority on May 8, 2014. 

This information is further addressed to any user consulting the web-based services that are made available by Blasting via its electronic networks. 

The information provided herein only applies to the use of the website of Blasting, and does not extend to any other websites that may be visited by any user via external links. 

The processing of your personal data (e.g., name, address, telephone number, email address, age, sex, user generated information such as financial interests, shopping habits, etc.., and all other data which have been provided to us by you voluntarily) (the “ _Personal Data_ ”) which is already or which will be in our possession, is and will be carried out in full compliance with the principles of correctness, transparency and confidentiality, in accordance with any applicable legal provisions protecting these principles. 

Your Personal Data may be subject to collection, registration, organization, preservation, consultation, elaboration, modification, selection, extraction, comparison, use, interconnection, blocking, communication, diffusion, transmission, resale, cancellation and destruction (the “ _Collection and Processing_ ”). One or more of those operations may be performed on your Personal Data with manual, electronic, computer or communication instruments, with methods and means that are appropriate in order to ensure the security of the Personal Data. The Personal Data may be archived either in paper form or electronically and shall be kept stored by Blasting for commercial purposes for a period strictly pertinent to such purposes, and, in any case, for a maximum term of 10 years, solely in relation to instructions or requests received by the Swiss, Italian or other competent authorities. 

Subject to the conditions and for the purposes described above, the Personal Data Collection and Processing may be carried out, on behalf of Blasting, by third partiesthat provide specific custody, organization, preservation and/or filing services to Blasting, which third parties are and will be responsible for their processing of the Personal Data. 

Our website and marketing emails may contain links to offers from third parties. Blasting has no influence on how other providers on linked websites handle the information displayed on these sites. If you have any questions in this regard, please contact these third parties directly. We are not responsible for upholding the data protection regulations in relation to these websites or for their content. By using this website, you agree and acknowledge the Collection and Processing of your Personal Data in the manner and for the purpose herein described. 

**The Collection and Processing of your Personal Data shall be carried out exclusively for the following purposes:**

  * the improvement of our services and the possibilities of their usage;
  * the development of our website and of affiliated companies;
  * the collection of statistical data and their evaluation;
  * the enhancement of our customer- and client-base;
  * the maintenance and improvement of relations with yourself, our customers and clients;
  * the maintenance of business relations with third parties;
  * our own marketing and sale activities in general;
  * marketing and sale activities of third parties;
  * other use in the interest of Blasting.

**Your Personal Data in our possession may also be communicated to third parties** , for the purposes indicated above, in Switzerland, Italy and in [other countries](https://www.blastingnews.com/list-of-countries/) identified on our website, namely but not exclusively to entities which are part of the corporate group of Blasting; other entities which are involved in subscription processes, sale and management operations; entities performing banking, financial and other outsourced services for Blasting; entities performing internet support services; entities which are in general business partners of Blasting; supervisory authorities of internet activities; and supervisory authorities for journalism and media related matters. These third parties shall act independently from Blasting, unless they are designated data processors. Your Personal Data shall not otherwise be subject to public disclosure. 

Blasting has no influence on how such third parties handle the information received and is not responsible for the observance of data protection regulations by these third parties. 

Employees or consultants of Blasting as well as of third parties that provide support services to Blasting, may come to know your Personal Data. These individuals or entities shall operate as data processors or persons in charge of the processing. 

We shall ask for your express consent to the treatment and processing of Personal Data whenever possible. In some specific cases, we assume your consent based on your actions and mode of behavior. By using the website **www.blastingnews.com** and related websites indicated therein you consent to the Collection and Processing of your Personal Data. Should you not consent to the above describe usage of your Personal Data, we kindly ask you to refrain from the usage of our website and related sites. 

**Policy processing of imported contacts by users.**

In order to improve a smooth functioning of the services offered by Blasting, it may send messages by automated systems (e.g. email, SMS or MMS) to contacts imported by you in relation to the use of on-site services, including among others - as an example - the news sharing or inviting friends services. We shall ask for express consent to the treatment and processing of Personal Data of such third party contacts whenever possible. In some specific cases we assume consent by such third party contacts based on their actions and mode of behavior. 

**Your rights with respect to your Personal Data** include the right: ( _a_ ) to receive confirmation of the existence of and information on any Personal Data relating to you, at any time and even if they are not already processed; ( _b_ ) to be informed about the source of the data, purposes and methods of the Collection and Processing, the rationale of any Collection and Processing carried out through electronic means, the details of the data controller and of any data processors and the entities or categories of entities to which the Personal Data may be communicated or which may get to know such data; ( _c_ ) to obtain ( _i_ ) the updating, rectification and integration of your Personal Data, ( _ii_ ) the cancellation, transformation into anonymous form or blocking of Personal Data that has been processed unlawfully, including data whose retention is unnecessary for the purposes for which it has been collected or subsequently processed, and ( _iii_ ) a certification to the effect that the operations described in the foregoing items ( _i_ ) and ( _ii_ ) and their content have been notified to those third parties to which the Personal Data has been communicated and/or distributed, unless this requirement proves impossible or involves an effort that is manifestly disproportionate to the right that should be protected ( _e.g._ , in cases where Personal Data has been transmitted by third parties to other entities unknown to Blasting); and ( _d_ ) to object, in whole or in part, on legitimate grounds, to the Collection and Processing of your Personal Data, even if Personal Data has been collected or processed purposefully. Note that in the latter case, your usage of the website **www.blastingnews.com** will no longer be possible. 

**Your data controller** is Blasting Sagl, with registered offices in Chiasso, Via Livio 14, CH-6830 Switzerland, and your data processor, to whom you may refer in order to exercise the abovementioned rights, is Blasting’s director of administration _pro tempore_ , domiciled for this purpose at Blasting’s registered offices, who also keeps an updated list of data processors. 

**Blasting’s Italian representative** is Andrea Manfredi, which is appointed to ensure the implementation of the Italian provisions concerning the Collection and Processing of your Personal Data pursuant to section 5, paragraph 2, of the Privacy Code. 

To request information regarding your data and/or about the exercise of the above- mentioned rights, kindly send an email to [staff@blastingnews.com](mailto:staff@blastingnews.com). 

Please keep in mind that you may revoke your consent at anytime. 

## Cookies

**What is a cookie?**

**In order to improve its customer services and for marketing activities, Blasting uses cookies** (a small file sent from the web server to the customer’s internet browser and saved in the customer’s computer). When you visit a website which uses cookies, such website sends small text snippets from the web server to the user’s internet browser and saves them in the user’s personal computer. At your next visit on that website, these files will be re-sent to the website that generated them in order to improve your use of the site in question. 

“Third parties” cookies, on the other hand, are sent from websites that you are not directly visiting. It occurs namely when accessing certain elements (like images, links, etc.) that are hosted by a different server from the one of the visited website. 

Some cookies are necessary for the correct use of the website and cannot be disabled. Others, like the ones regarding memorization of preference parameters, can be disabled. 

The advantage for a user to have cookies installed on his/her computer consists in the fact that he/she is no longer required to provide the same information every time he/ she accesses the same website, as his/her personal information is remembered by the website through the cookies. 

**What are cookies needed for?**

Cookies help to improve our services and your browsing experience. There are various kinds of cookies, each one having a specific purpose. Blasting uses the following cookies: 

**Technical cookies or “first-party” cookies**

These cookies are managed by the owner and/or the publisher of the website and are strictly needed for the proper operation of the website but also provide aggregate data for internal surveys regarding the numbers of website-visits, the popularity of the website and traffic flow information. 

In order to install these cookies, the consent of the user is not required (essentially as all data collected remains anonymized). Nonetheless, the administrator of the website shall provide the user with the information deemed appropriate and in line with section 13 of the Privacy Code. 

Technical cookies do not collect information that may be used for advertisements, neither do they track the users’ personal browsing history. 

Given the technical and impersonal character of these cookies, the user is generally not required to accept this kind of cookies, as stated by the provision “ _Simplified Arrangements to Provide Information and Obtain Consent Regarding Cookies_ ”, issued by the Italian Data Protection Authority on May 8, 2014.1 However, if the user denies the installation of the cookies, his/her access to the website is denied as well. 

**Profiling cookies**

Profiling Cookies are used to create user profiles and are installed in order to send advertising messages according to the preferences of the user identified by the cookies. 

Considering the resulting interference with privacy such cookies entail, the legislator requires the websites to properly inform their users regarding the installation of such cookies and allows the installation only upon express consent by the user. 

**“Third party” cookies**

These cookies are installed on the user’s browser by a party that is not the owner and/ or the publisher of the visited website. There are various types of such “third party” cookies, among which: 

Analytics Cookies: used to collect and analyze data. They do not identify the individual user. 

Advertising Cookies: applied to understand and store user preferences for advertising purposes during the user’s online browsing. Blasting has no influence on the use of cookies installed by entities or third parties linked to its website and declines all responsibility thereto. 

**NAI Policy**

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. 

**How to disable cookies?**

Through the use of the website **www.blastingnews.com** , the user’s consent to the installation of cookies is assumed by Blasting. Users and customers who do not wish to receive cookies may block “first party”, “profiling” and/or “third party” cookies following the instructions provided by each browser, set forth hereinafter. 

For further information on third parties installing cookies on our websites, with which direct or indirect commercial relations have been established by Blasting, kindly refer to the respective information on the Privacy Policy of such third parties. 

In order to delete cookies stored on your computer, please refer to the guide of your browser and follow the instructions. 

**Please note that by disabling “first party” cookies, you will not be able to navigate our website.**

## Copyright Transfer Agreement

Please [click here for your copy of the Copyright Transfer Agreement](https://static.blastingnews.com/media/pdf/Blasting_News_Contratto.pdf). Acceptance of the terms and conditions set out in said document are an obligatory condition for usage of the Blasting News platform.
